Tiago Patricio Santos

tiagopatriciosantos@gmail.com | (+351)965162567 | Leiria, Portugal LinkedIn: tiagopatriciosantos | Portfolio: https://tiagopatriciosantos.github.io

Summary:

Data Science/Machine Learning Engineer with extensive experience in software engineering and deep learning. Proficient in C#, SQL, and Python. Certified in Data Science Professional and Data Analyst Associate from DataCamp, as well as Deep Learning Specialization from DeepLearning.Al. Demonstrated ability to perform data management, exploratory analysis, statistical experimentation, model development, coding for production environments, communication, and reporting. Proven success as a team leader, project manager, and software developer in the oil and gas industry and implementing ERP solutions. Fluent in Portuguese and English.

Skills:

- Expertise in deep learning algorithms and techniques
- Data management and analysis
- Model development and optimization
- Coding for production environments -Data visualization and communication
- Strong problem-solving and troubleshooting skills
- Excellent work ethic and positive attitude
- Reliable and trustworthy

Programming Languages:

- Python
- C#
- VB .Net
- SQL

Education and Training:

- Data Scientist Professional Certification | DataCamp | Nov 2022
- Data Analyst Associate Certification | DataCamp | Sep 2022
- Data Engineer with Python Certification | DataCamp | Jul 2022
- Deep Learning Specialization | DeepLearning.Al | Feb 2022
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering | ESTG, Leiria, Portugal | 2007

Experience:

Machine Learning Engineer | Identify Fake Job Posting | Personal Project | Jan 2023 - Current

- Successfully developed a solution to identify fake job postings
- Conducted exploratory data analysis and utilized Scikit-learn's algorithms to evaluate the model's performance

- Demonstrated proficiency in version control tools like DagsHub and DVC, as well as experiment tracking tools like MLFlow, to create a reproducible and version-controlled data science project.
- Deployed the model as a WebAPI using FastAPI and Mogenius, showcasing an end-to-end understanding of ML development and deployment.

Software Engineer | (Freelancer) | January 2021 – Current

- Consultant for ERP Primavera
- Develop software solutions for clients

Team Leader | Trigénius S.A. | Fátima, Portugal | October 2019 - December 2020

- Managed a team of 11 in the Primavera ERP Functional department
- Project manager for software implementation projects
- Developed software solutions for clients

Software Engineer | Somoil S.A. | Luanda, Angola | October 2013 - December 2018

- Team leader of 3 in support of Primavera ERP BSS
- Analyzed and defined business processes and prepared project documentation
- Developed software solutions and trained and supported users

Software Engineer | Trigénius S.A. | Fátima, Portugal | January 2007 - October 2013

- Implemented ERP solutions, mainly SAP Business One and Primavera BSS ERP
- Analyzed and defined business processes of organizations and prepared project documentation and deadlines proposals
- Developed software solutions for clients

Languages:

• Portuguese: First Language

· English: Advanced